<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on On the moon</title><link>http://onthemoon.net/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on On the moon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:37:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://onthemoon.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2. Fractal processing server example - part 1</title><link>http://onthemoon.net/post/2020-07-15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 20:37:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://onthemoon.net/post/2020-07-15/</guid><description>Today I want to discuss a simple example for a notification server, which is often given as a first exercise for developers new to the framework. This will be a variation of the usual exercise, so I can demonstrate some of the core concepts. The notification server we want to implement today is a server that generates pictures of fractals. For those of you who are not familiar with fractals, these are mathematical shapes with self-symmetry.</description></item><item><title>1. The notification server</title><link>http://onthemoon.net/post/2020-07-11/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 12:27:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://onthemoon.net/post/2020-07-11/</guid><description>So, we&amp;rsquo;re about to begin this journey. Before discussing how to implement a notification server, I should probably explain first what we are trying to build. That is what is a notification server?
Everyone has their own viewpoint on this, and here I will describe my own. A notification server is a box which consists of components which are linked to each other. It could be thought of as an engine, where each component is thought as a gear in the engine&amp;rsquo;s gearbox.</description></item><item><title>ConsoleHost.Run(args)</title><link>http://onthemoon.net/post/2020-07-08/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 22:58:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://onthemoon.net/post/2020-07-08/</guid><description>This blog is dedicated to the notification server project, a well established project which many have devoted their time to its development.
I decided to start this blog for two reasons. One is an educational reason: this blog should allow one to understand the underlying concepts of the notification server project, and ultimately will allow them to write their own implementation, with the perspectives and thoughts viewed in this blog in mind.</description></item></channel></rss>